<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sxsw | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/sxsw/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-10T14:09:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW isn't for Backend Devs Anymore]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2011/03/16/sxsw-isnt-for-backend-devs-anymore/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2011/03/16/sxsw-isnt-for-backend-devs-anymore</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my time at the interactive portion of SXSW, I was looking for great
technical panels on practical ways to improve my technical skills. While I
found a bunch of panels that addressed some interesting issues, I don't think
I saw any server side code the entire time I was there. There were a number of
great CSS and HTML5 talks, but aside from the PHP workshop that was listed at
the wrong time in the booklet, I found no practical talks for backend
developers.</p>

<p>Over the past couple years, it seems like there has definitely been a shift in
how sxsw views technical talks. Two years ago, there were developers
presenting great content on how to structure APIs, write great PHP, and
develop iPhone / Android Apps. This year, the php workshop had the incorrect
time printed in the booklet. The technical talks this year seemed be designed
for the nontechnical. The discussions around scaling included big names
quoting scaling statistics that are sure to be taken out of context and read
as homily by technical managers everywhere. The Android Developer meetup was
almost completely devoid of Android devs, just sharks looking for them, myself
included. The panel on the death of the RDBMS painted a rosy picture of what
databases could be, but did not include a mention of a single technology that
fit the presenter's pipe dream.</p>

<p>The ubiquitousness of the term social media at SXSW leaves me with one
conclusion. SXSW has changed from a gathering that was about people doing cool
stuff to a group of people talking about stuff they think is cool right now.
There has been a lot of discussion on conversation, but not much conversation
on how to create things worth talking about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Progress Bar Pysch]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2011/03/12/the-progress-bar-pysch/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2011/03/12/the-progress-bar-pysch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A classic UX problems is communicating to users how long they'll have to wait
before their task completes. A spinner or progress bar provides feedback that
the system is, in fact, doing something, and how long that task may take.
Psychologically, progress bars create tension while progressing, and
resolution when completed.</p>

<p>From a technical standpoint, progress bars are black magic. The developer is
attempting to estimate a task based on potentially thousands of variables. In
the case of a file upload, the developer has to deal with differing network
conditions, disk performance, etc, etc, etc. Then they have to write the code
to communicate what is happening to the browser. Not a trivial task. However,
when executed well, can provide the user with reasonable feedback about their
task.</p>

<p>Lately, sites like LinkedIn, Mint.com, and OKCupid have used that same tension
to motivate users to completely fill out their profiles. During profile
creation, a progress bar is displayed indicating how far the user has come
along. Once the user completely fills out their profile, the progress bar hits
100%, and what changes? In most cases, nothing. The progress bar is just a
psychological hack to entice users to go through the entire process.</p>

<p>The question is: Exactly how effective is the progress bar at enticing users
to fully complete the task at hand? And are they actually worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
