<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Horror Stories | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/horror-stories/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-03T23:00:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergencies will audit the shit out of you]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/10/21/emergencies-will-audit-the-shit-out-of-you/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/10/21/emergencies-will-audit-the-shit-out-of-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Things never go wrong at convenient times: Like when you're auditing the
latest, coolest version of your app, and looking for bugs. Things have a funny
way of working out fine <strong>then</strong>. However, soon as you look the other way, a
multitude of problems come out of the woodwork. It usually goes something like
this:</p>

<p>One server goes down, and the system that was supposed to fail silently starts
screaming. The application it was supporting goes down, because the proper
timeouts and error handling was never written. You can't fail over, because
failing over will take down 2 other applications. When that first server comes
back up, nothing works, because the proper startup scripts were never put in
place. Once the right services start, if you can remember what the hell they
were, you find the original application is configured wrong. Not only is it
configured wrong, it's <strong><em>always</em></strong> been configured wrong, and no one noticed.
No one noticed because it only explodes in the exact set of horrible
circumstances you have right now. Which is, by the way, being down.</p>

<p>It's an all-too-familiar story, and one that even most the anal of admins has
dealt with. The fact of the matter is that it is going to happen, and there's
not a whole lot you can do to prepare, other than randomly pulling plugs out
of servers. But with any mistake that causes downtime, it should <a href="http://l.chr.ishenry.com/fail">only happen
once</a>. Proper postmortem examination needs to
be taken here to figure out what went wrong where. Once all the variables are
understood, the next step is to duplicate the same set of circumstances in
your <a href="http://l.chr.ishenry.com/sbx">sandbox</a>, and apply the necessary error
handling.</p>

<p>Downtime and emergencies are a part of running any site. What's really
important is to treat emergencies as an opportunity to learn about what
happens when systems fail, for real.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search is Hard]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/10/09/search-is-hard/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/10/09/search-is-hard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The title of this post is a direct quote from a Facebook engineer presenting
at the SXSW panel <a href="http://my.sxsw.com/events/event/386">Beyond Lamp</a>. Search
is a critical function of any site, but its gotten much much harder as Google
has gotten better. To quote the Beyond Lamp panel one more time:</p>

<blockquote><p>Search is always compared against Google, which is like comparing the canoe
you just built to the QE2.</p></blockquote>

<p>The difficulty of search is made apparent by the majority of sites, even major
sites get it wrong. A large factor in the success of search is relevancy.
Google takes into account <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank">500 million
variables</a> in determining how relevant
content is. Not only that, but they also know who you are, what you've
clicked, and can make decisions based on that to present pages that are more
relevant to you. Facebook's EdgeRank, LinkedIn's Signal are other examples of
search implementations that are vast in scale.</p>

<p>In a startup, where time is of the essence and resources need to be begged,
borrowed or stolen, search is a huge challenge. Like trying to be build the
QE2 with nothing but a swiss army knife. Basic tools normally don't cut it.
MySQL's FULLTEXT indexes are helpful, but start trying to implement basic IR
techniques like booleans, and MySQL's builtin functionality starts to lack the
ability to get the results your want.</p>

<p>There are ways to simplify building search.
<a href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/01/28/sphinx-full-text-search-engine/">Sphinx</a>
provides great matching capabilities and incredibly fast sorting. When
combined with other data, Sphinx can be a great way to get users fast,
meaningful results. The one downside with using a document based search engine
is that there is little room for returning completely tailored results. Unlike
MySQL, which allows you to slice and dice data in any way you choose, it is
more difficult to return results that take into account relationship specific
to users and documents. However, for most search tasks, it should function
very well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It happens to everyone...]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/09/26/it-happens-to-everyone/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/09/26/it-happens-to-everyone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Through a combination of unhealthy fears, paranoid tendencies, and luck, I've
been able to avoid that unavoidable situation that every sysadmin fears:
completely nuking a system. Until last Tuesday, when I did something really,
really dumb. On the server that hosts
<a href="http://chr.ishenry.com">http://chr.ishenry.com</a>, I had noticed a script,
<a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=svcrack.py">svcrack.py</a>, running and consuming lots of
resources, and bandwidth, as I would later find out from my hosting bill.</p>

<p>Since I sure as hell wasn't running that, I could only assume that someone had
exploited my server and was using it to look for unsecured voip installations.
Initially, I assumed killing the scripts and changing some passwords would be
sufficient. However, checking in the server later, I found the same script
running. All this is fair enough, as I am on Wordpress, a few versions behind,
and there are enough folders with unhealthy permissions that I kind of
deserved it. So after a few days of trying to lock things down, I got a bit
desperate.</p>

<p>Since svcrack is a python script, there was a good chance the best way to
discourage my assailant would be to remove python. Great idea in theory, but
it seemed my execution was a bit poor. It turns out running 'yum remove
python' is a great way to destroy your entire system. yum runs on python,
which meant a reinstall would have to be done manually. Only problem, most of
the shell bultins stopped working as well. cp, mv, ls all resulted in a
'command not found' error. The best part of this situation: no backups. After
all the <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2009/12/international-backup-%0Aawareness-day.html">hubbub about blogs and
backups</a> lately, it's kind of amazing I missed this rather
important detail.</p>

<p>I've always considered data loss the cardinal sin in development, web or
otherwise. However, I also never considered my personal site to be mission
critical, or worthy of taking the the time for backups. But as they say, you
never know what you have till it's gone. I was lucky enough that mysql and
apache were still running, and I was able to export everything, spin up a new
server, and import. Even with no data loss, this is certainly a lesson
learned. I am making a backup right now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gmail actually gets something really wrong.]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/08/16/gmail-actually-gets-something-really-wrong/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2010/08/16/gmail-actually-gets-something-really-wrong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm a huge fan of Gmail and Google Apps for
<a href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2009/04/26/just-manage-it-for-me/">many</a> reasons. I
love the new redesign, and how they're finally promoting consistency across
their major webapps. It makes me feel like the web could <em>really</em> be a viable
alternative alternative to desktop software. I can even deal with
<a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2010/06/gmail-performance-issues.html">slowness</a> in
Gmail, given the amount of work they need to do in order to keep your inbox
snappy. They need to index every message, which means parsing every message,
converting every attachment, and linking it the search architecture. In real
time. Not easy…</p>

<p>However, what I found today, was completely inexcusable: Gmail's clipping
"feature". This is definitely a feature that sounds a lot more like a bug than
a helpful tool.</p>

<p><a href="/images/user/gmail_clipping.png"><img src="/images/user/gmail_clipping.png" alt="Gmail Message clipping" /></a></p>

<p>What <em>should</em> be here is a few more links, some mouse text that contains our
mailing address and unsubscribe links. What I did not show in this screenshot
is the capacity for destruction this feature has on HTML emails. When the
email is 'clipped', the HTML is broken at a random place, and not displayed.
If your message is clipped at an inopportune place, there goes your entire
HTML layout. In the best case, your HTML is simply truncated, leaving users
with only a piece of their email.</p>

<p>As the entity sending this email, the responsibility falls on me to make sure
that I send emails that are accessible, conform to CAN-SPAM, and are pleasing
to the eye. Gmail bones me on three of these goals. Thanks to a
<a href="http://mail.google.com/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=9377">lack</a> of
<a href="http://tinyurl.com/2asve9s">documentation</a> as to how long an email can be
without invoking the clipping feature. Most importantly, my users have no
clear to unsubscribe from the list, since the most likely links to be clipped
are the unsubscribe links.</p>

<p>I agree that
<a href="http://mail.google.com/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=9377">performance</a>
is king, but never at the cost of the user.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> It seems like Gmail limits messages to around 102k characters before clipping. So the solution seems to be running HTML through a compressor. I found a pretty good one <a href="http://www.textfixer.com/html/compress-html-compression.php">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rackspace Downtime]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2009/11/04/rackspace-downtime/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2009/11/04/rackspace-downtime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[Update] My team at Rackspace has sent me the fluffiest, most comfortable
pillow I have ever had.</p>

<p>When a hosting provider goes down, there are lots of questions that get
raised. Is my host reliable? Will they flake out during crucial times when my
site needs the traffic? Will they <a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=dreamhost+billing">double
bill</a> me?</p>

<p>Since I have been working with Rackspace, they have had less than stellar
uptime, with issues mostly related to power. My company pays a lot for hosting
with them, and downtime for a young company is deadly. But oddly enough, I'm
still OK with Rackspace hosting my company's myriad services. The benefits of
hosting with them have been so great that a couple hours of downtime is
nothing.</p>

<p>First off, their SLA has provisions for downtime, when it happens. If your
server has a legitimate issue, you're entitled to ask for a credit. To me,
this is a promise that they'll put their money where their mouth is. And if
you call them on it, they'll be reasonable.</p>

<p>Secondly, their support during crises is still amazing. During the <a href="http://bit.ly/9LrNz">truck
incident</a>, I was able to get a tech to run fsck on my
disks, and hang out to watch no questions asked. No, I am not on their
intensive plan.</p>

<p>Third, their support culture is simply amazing. Their linux techs are always
willing to look deep into an issue to find a resolution, and they provide much
of the basic <a href="http://bit.ly/1HkKYJ">infrastructure</a> that is hard to come by
for small companies.. They're also completely willing to educate their
customers about the servers they maintain.</p>

<p>In short, Rackspace has been the target of a lot of criticism over issues in
their datacenters. The fact of the matter is that there will always be issues
and downtime. <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/solutions/managed_hosting/s%0Aupport/servicelevels/managedsla.php">Their SLA</a> guarantees the impossible, which they
seem to realize, as any failure on their part comes with swift response. In
the end their SLA seems to be more of a way of setting standards than anything
else.</p>

<p>[Full disclosure: I haven't slept in 2 days because of their power issues]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
