<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tools | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-12T19:32:06-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RSS Resolution, and Blog Updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/06/30/blog-updates/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-30T20:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/06/30/blog-updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After much neglect, and a few insane weeks, I've finally gotten the time to update a few things in my daily toolkit. First, RSS; I've decided to go all in with <a href="http://www.feedly.com" target="_blank">Feedly</a>. I've found it to be a great cross-platform candidate that's had to deal with a <a href="http://blog.feedly.com/2013/06/21/summary-of-the-last-100-days/">lot of scaling challenges</a> in a very, very short period of time. I give them a lot of credit for building a massive platform and being able to continue to add features to what looks like a web app with great potential. At the moment, my only real gripe would be a progress indicator in the browser of the iOS app.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Secondly, I've made a few small updates to this very site. Since Twitter has deprecated v1 of their API, which the <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> supplied twitter widget depends on, has crapped out. Since I've been all about minimalism lately, it seemed appropriate to simply pull the plug on it. That decision led me down the rabbit hole of how to update Octopress themes. (Hint: if you are using a theme, and you edit sass and html files in source, <a href="http://i95.photobucket.com/albums/l142/gstatejester/02-youre-doing-it-wrong.jpg?t=1285658433" target="_blank">you're doing it wrong</a>.) That revelation led me to forking the venerable <a href="https://github.com/tommy351/Octopress-Theme-Slash">Slash</a> Octopress theme. <a href="https://github.com/chrishenry/Octopress-Theme-Slash">My own fork</a> loses the Twitter feed, narrows the layout a bit, and adds an Add to Feedly link.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSH tunnels made easy]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/01/27/ssh-tunnels-made-easy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/01/27/ssh-tunnels-made-easy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the classic problems in administering databases is providing secure,
yet accessible tools for all those who need to run queries or examine
production data. Classically, phpMyAdmin has been a great tool for handling
MySQL for those who don't know the command line. However, as any sysadmin
worth his salt knows, it's an extremely insecure tool for a couple of reasons.</p>

<ul>
<li>It requires php, and specific modules, which is just one more thing to install.</li>
<li>It requires apache.</li>
<li>Apache requires port 80 to be open.</li>
</ul>


<p>All of these things are bad, since garden variety attackers and script kiddies
can potentially find your phpmyadmin installation. Since phpMyAdmin is open-
source, and freely available, there always likely to be security holes. One of
the best ways around this is to close phpMyAdmin off to the public via
firewall, and then use an SSH tunnel to pass traffic through another server.
The server hosting mysql and phpMyAdmin can safely stay hidden, with all ports
closed.</p>

<p><img src="/images/user/ssh_tunnel_diagram.gif" alt="Diagram, showing the flow of traffic between client and secure mysql server.
" /></p>

<p>Set up looks something like this (on a Mac, at least).</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Install <a href="http://www.macports.org/install.php">MacPorts</a></p></li>
<li><p>Install Xcode command line dev tools.</p></li>
</ol>


<blockquote><p>Open Xcode -> Preferences -> Downloads -> Command Line Tools</p></blockquote>

<ol>
<li>Install <a href="http://www.harding.motd.ca/autossh/">autossh</a> , which is a tool for opening an ssh connection, and making sure it stays open. I use MacPorts to install it. <a href="http://www.macports.org/">http://www.macports.org/</a></li>
</ol>


<blockquote><p>$ sudo port install autossh</p></blockquote>

<ol>
<li>Once that's installed, you can run something like this. (Make sure that the port is the port that you configured Apache to accept traffic on.)</li>
</ol>


<blockquote><p>autossh -M 20002 -f -L 7422:your.db.served.biz.org:7422 your.jump.server.biz
"sleep 99999999999"</p></blockquote>

<ol>
<li>From there, you can open phpMyAdmin at a URL like http://localhost:7422/phpMyAdmin. One very convenient way to wrap all this up is to use the automator app.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="/images/user/ssh_tunnel_auto.png" alt="Automator screenshot" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
