<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-18T14:43:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Volunteering at Hour of Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/12/17/volunteering-at-hour-of-code/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-17T22:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/12/17/volunteering-at-hour-of-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, as part of the Hour of Code, I went to <a href="http://ithsnyc.org/2013/home">Information Technology High
School</a> in Long Island City. I spent the morning
talking to students about what it's like to work in Web Operations.</p>

<p>It was amazing seeing students taking an interest in technology and coding. Many
of them had already completed the <a href="https://hourofcode.com/us">Hour of Code</a>
projects. Others were still tinkering, seeing what they could add and change. I
spent some time critiquing and reviewing work they had done in Mrs. Ramirez's
Web Design class. The students had all created functional portfolio sites,
complete with content, small bits of javascript, and even Flash games.</p>

<p>The students were interested in my day to day, and the path I took to get
where I am in my career. The students were amazed to hear that I didn't work in
a dark closet by myself, but in a brightly lit office constantly interacting
with colleagues. They were also amazed to hear that the skills they needed to be
truly successful in tech weren't just coding and hardware, but communication,
teamwork, and judgment. How a college education fit in to a career in Web
Operations came up a few times. It was particularly interesting because I'm not
aware of any four year university that offers a program in the field.</p>

<p>Students were particularly interested to hear about about some of the
work I've done around security and incident response. Tales of defending
against <a href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/07/29/what-it-feels-like-to-be-ddosed/">DDoS</a>
and spam attacks were a great way to let them know that career paths in tech
aren't just limited to coding or back office IT. They were spellbound to hear
that mitigating DDoS attacks were actually something that could be part
of an actual career path, and not just something they see in TV and movies. I
truly hope that some students are inspired to pursue a career in Systems
Administration and Web Operations.</p>

<p>One thing that was made clear to me as I was asked to describe my path to Web
Operations was there is no clear path, and that sad fact has resulted in a
shortage of people in the field. I would encourage other folks in Web Operations
to spend some time talking to young students about the work that we do in the
hopes that in a few years the industry will grow and mature. After all, for
every class that learns to code, there need to be a few students who know
how to run the infrastructure for that code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Burnout]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/11/07/burnout/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-07T18:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/11/07/burnout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was 4:43 PM. As I headed out the door, someone asked, "Leaving early?" No
malice, no judgment, just a bit of surprise. The office was still full,
keyboards clicking and the drone of technical conversation dully throbbing. "I'm
entitled to it, I just worked an incident for 3 days straight," I shot back.</p>

<p>Was I entitled to bail early? Probably, but that wasn't the right way to say it.
I <strong>needed</strong> to leave. Despite handling the incident deftly, I still felt
fucking awful, and in a dark, looming, nonspecific way. I needed to run from the
firehose of problems, lack of solutions, apathy and anxiety. The incident in
question was a days-long spam attack. It wasn't my first rodeo with hackers, but
this mitigation required bringing several groups together, which is always a
challenge at a large organization. To add to that, there was a pronounced lack
of resources from my own team. This attack came at a time when we were gearing
up to launch a new product, and the team was completely focused on it. Even I
had been intensely involved with ensuring the stability of a new, shaky
platform. Being pulled away just added to my frustration.</p>

<p>I had already spoken with my manager that afternoon, told him I was tired. He
kindly ordered me to go home, and take a vacation. I took the next two days off,
calling in sick. This was the second time in a month I'd unexpectedly needed
time off. At home, I crashed, played video games, watched a bunch of shitty
movies my girlfriend normally wouldn't palate, and generally just tried to avoid
the real world. Physically, I wasn't all that tired, considering I had only
slept 9 hours or so over the past 3 days. But my mind and nerves were totally
shot, and worse, I felt like I didn't care, which I hated myself for.</p>

<p>In short, I burned out. Hard.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>Burnout is a state of emotional, mental, and physical exhaustion caused by<br/>excessive and prolonged stress. It manifests itself in ways including anxiety,<br/>loss of motivation and confidence, and even degradation of physical health.<br/>Burnout can be prevalent in organizations that promote hero culture and where<br/>employees maintain a strong a sense of duty...</p></blockquote></p>

<p>--- <a href="http://burnout.io/">Burnout.io</a></p>

<p>I lead operations at a small part of a large company, and I've been there a very
long time. My mission is to ensure the company's online presence is up and
safe. Admittedly, my sense of duty to the mission has always been somewhat
overzealous. In fact, much of my identity is tied up in the job I do. Those
sentiments have truly been assets in navigating a treacherous path, but it
seemed clear that they have become a double edged sword. Once I got bored with
Xbox, I went through a journal I've been keeping for a few years.</p>

<p>In it, there were multiple notes and rants pointing to the simple fact that I
have an unhealthy work-life balance. I found a long running list of songs to
learn on guitar, but I haven't picked up my guitar in several months. I have
notes on code projects I started but didn't make any progress on for years.
There are links to museum exhibits I wanted to visit that closed long ago.
Reading through, I also realized I don't have any more than a handful of friends
outside of work. All in all, it was a pattern of regret.</p>

<p>But also a lot of reasons to make some changes. Burnout is caused by a
combination of internal and external factors, some of which can be managed. My
biggest realization, looking through my past, is that I don't need a vacation, I
need a change in how I manage my energy with regard to my sense of duty to my
work. I need to be more cognizant of how I feel when external factors rear
their head, recognize signs of nearing the burnout zone, and back away.
Presented without comment, are my signs of burnout;</p>

<ul>
<li>Saying "No" to everything, even the reasonable things</li>
<li>Shortness with team members during normal interactions</li>
<li>Feeling like I've made no forward momentum</li>
<li>Inability to express myself</li>
<li>Constant <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amygdala_hijack">amygdala hijack</a></li>
<li>Inability to stay on task, or read anything longer than an email</li>
<li>Many nights in a row falling asleep while attempting to watch the same
episode of John Oliver</li>
</ul>


<p>Things I need to do to prevent getting to this place in the future;</p>

<ul>
<li>Tightly limit my hours</li>
<li>Let go of, or delegate certain things that I just don't need to do</li>
<li>Be OK with things not happening, and the failures that result</li>
<li>Commit to things I want to do; cooking, music, projects, and social events</li>
<li>Don't accept any new work unless I truly have the capacity to do it</li>
</ul>


<p>The other hard reality is that for me to affect this change, I will need to
attempt to manage the external factors. There are going to be some failures, but
I'll need to be OK with that, or I'll have to make bigger changes. I truly love
what I do, but now is the time for me to take some of myself back.</p>

<p>Wish me luck.</p>

<p>A few great burnout resources that helped me write this;</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://burnout.io/">burnout.io</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kentnguyen.com/personal/getting-rid-burnouts/">Getting rid of burnout</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.usenix.org/node/186465">Burnout and Ops; Lars Lehtonen</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/104252736">From Hero to Zero; Jennifer Davis</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
