<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tumblr | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/tumblr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-02T18:01:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/02/09/switching-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-09T16:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/02/09/switching-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month, I decided to refresh my blogging platform. My Wordpress was old and busted, and working on it didn't quite fit with the way I wanted to work. I tried tumblr for a few weeks, but it felt pretty constraining. Overall, I was looking for a platform that gave me control, and the ability to crack open the source and do what I wanted.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Overall, here were the features I was looking for</p>

<ul>
<li>Display code beautifully, right off the bat.</li>
<li>Add plugins. Maybe even write them myself.</li>
<li>Be able to have all my content organized how I want.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> was a perfect fit. Working with git, the command line, and markdown are all things that are very familiar to me. There's a great community around it, and enough open development around it to support most of the things I want to do. And if the community hasn't built it yet, then I can certainly give it a try myself.</p>

<p>The docs on the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">Octopress</a> site are really good. Aside from the typical challenges of upgrading Ruby on Mac. <a href="http://www.macports.org/">MacPorts</a> was extremely helpful with the upgrade to Ruby 1.9.3.  Also, the provisioning of a Heroku dyno, and the deploy was as close to painless as it gets.</p>

<p>The migration, however, was not quite as simple. I had plenty of trouble getting my content into tumblr, and I also had a bit of trouble getting it out. Tom Preston-Warner's <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/blog-migrations">github wiki</a> was very helpful. However, be aware that the default ruby gems are a little out of date, and the information <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues/773">this resolved issue</a> helped get around the trouble.</p>

<p>Once the posts were actually imported, there still needed to be a bit of massaging done to get them into shape. The yaml header was using tags instead of categories. In the source/_posts folder, a quick sed command got me what I wanted.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Sed snippet  </span></figcaption>
 <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">$ </span>sed -i <span class="s1">&#39;&#39;</span> <span class="s1">&#39;s/&lt;sup&gt;tags/categories/&#39;</span>&lt;/sup&gt; *
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>I do miss my old Wordpress blog, but it was definitely time for a change, as that had been my blog for years. Setting up Octopress has been a great experiment in looking at another language (ruby, and some python), getting more familiar with git, and getting even more acquainted with SublimeText.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
