<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-27T15:10:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flight Status]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2014/11/02/flight-status/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-02T16:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2014/11/02/flight-status</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I was stuck in an airport for a couple hours. I was flying to San Francisco, and upon arriving to JFK, was informed my flight would be delayed several hours due to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ground_delay_program">ground delay program</a>. A ground delay program is put in place when a particular airport's ability to keep up with traffic is diminished. If your destination airport has a program in place, your takeoff will be delayed until the destination recovers.</p>

<p>A ground delay program is the operations equivalent of shedding load. ATC essentially stops allowing inbound flights to take off to allow for the extra time and care it takes for en-route flights to land safely. This is very similar to <a href="http://techblog.netflix.com/2011/12/making-netflix-api-more-resilient.html">Netflix's implementation of the CircuitBreaker pattern</a>, as it allows the resource having trouble to recover while keeping flights en route at a minimum.</p>

<p>While I was stuck, I found there's a couple really neat tools that can tell you a little about your chances of getting there on time.</p>

<h4>FAA</h4>

<p>The FAA is kind enough to supply information on delays <a href="http://www.fly.faa.gov/flyfaa/usmap.jsp">here</a>. However, I found the information to be presented here a bit disingenuous. The map continued to show my destination airport as green, although flights were actually being held at departure points.</p>

<h4>FlightStats.com</h4>

<p><a href="http://www.flightstats.com">They</a> have a delay index where every destination airport is given a ranking of 0 through 5, 0 being totally on time, and 5 meaning go back to the airport bar and grab another beer. They also very helpfully track whether that index is trending up or down. These relate directly to how long a Ground Delay Program has been running. The longer that ground delay program runs, they more likely that index is going to going to trend up. They also provide a listing of flights to your destination airport that you can use to benchmark how delayed other flights and airlines are.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inn on Randolph]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/12/30/inn-on-randolph/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-30T17:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/12/30/inn-on-randolph</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This Christmas, <a href="http://sequinsandbobbypins.com/">Jessica</a> and I took a trip to Napa Valley. In the past year, I've taken quite a few trips out to California, but most of them have been helicopter trips for work. I've flown in, done what I needed to do, and flown out, as quickly as possible. These trips have been grueling, as they were designed to get me home quickly, and never allowed any time for relaxation. It seemed important to take a trip focused on getting to know an area.</p>

<p>We decided that we were going to spend a few days in Napa, so naturally, a B&amp;B was a great choice. We wanted to have breakfast provided, a bunch of other folks to chat with about life, and a warm, comfy place to call home for a couple days. We found the <a href="http://www.innonrandolph.com/">Inn on Randolph</a> via the Googlez, and were impressed by the comfortable looking rooms, so we booked. They offered a wine tour through <a href="http://www.platypustours.com/">Platypus Tours</a> so we booked it. It seemed like a good idea for 2 folks who haven't been behind the wheel in years to not be behind the wheel and drinking. That's about all the planning we did.</p>

<p>Upon arriving, we were greeted warmly, given freshly baked cookies and the lay of the land. Both Karen and Stacey were immensely knowledgeable about navigating Napa, and were able to recommend great places based on how we felt. What's more, it seems the Inn on Randolph has taken advantage of a great network of wine makers, restaurateurs, and tasting rooms to provide a great experience. Each morning at breakfast, Karen or Stacey would ask if we had plans, and if not, could they help. On their recommendation, they booked us into amazing experiences. For wineries they couldn't book us into, they provided tasting cards. Much of the value of staying at the Inn is the advice and access (read: free tastings) they provide. However, expect that to evaporate into wine purchases, as the recommendations will quickly turn into opportunities to buy very unique and delicious wines.</p>

<p>The Inn itself is gorgeous. It has a warm, comfortable palette of dark wood, grays, and cremes decorated with Victorian furniture. The Inn has also paid close attention to creature comforts that make for a truly relaxing stay away from home. The bathroom floors were heated, which makes the Inn the most luxuriant place I have ever stayed at. The beds were the kind that hug you and don't let go, with heavy comforters that make it difficult to leave. (The only way I was able to get up was knowing my feet wouldn't freeze on cold floors.)</p>

<p>All in all, this was an incredibly warm, comfortable way to spend a few days in wine country. The Inn aims to send folks to places that will educate and treat them well, and to provide a delightful place to roost at once they're done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rules for London]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/01/26/rules-for-london/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/01/26/rules-for-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, I took a trip to London and Paris. It was my first trip to
Europe. Having never been to Europe, or on a real vacation for the last couple
years, I was really looking to maximize my time there. So I had a couple rules
while for I was there;</p>

<ol>
<li>Have a long list of things to do, but no plan.</li>
<li>Walk or take public transportation everywhere.</li>
<li>Get to know the neighborhoods I'm staying in.</li>
<li>If something looks interesting, do it.</li>
<li>Don't be an #uglyamerican.</li>
</ol>


<p>As it turns out, those were some really great rules. The last thing I wanted
in a vacation was a schedule. Plus, if we got involved in something, and took
more time than we thought, it wouldn't matter. And following rule #2 the
entire and rule #4 the entire trip, there were plenty of things that we found
along the way that took up more time than we thought. The <a href="http://www.camdenlock.net/stables/index.html">Camden
Stalls</a>, for example, were full
of treasures and side alleys to explore.</p>

<p>Rule #2 turned out to be pretty great for a bunch of reasons. The London tube
is super efficient, clean, and has wifi. The only drawback of the Underground
is that it closes early, as does most of London. Walking a city is really the
only way to really get to know a city. Also, getting lost is the best way to
find the really cool stuff.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
