<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Advertising | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/categories/advertising/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-10T01:32:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[app.net, I smell a pattern]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2012/08/19/appnet-i-smell-a-pattern/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2012/08/19/appnet-i-smell-a-pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After being pummeled into submission by 42924 tweets about
<a href="https://join.app.net/">app.net,</a> I finally decided it was time to take a look
at what seemed like a very popular concept. If (IF) I understand correctly,
app.net is an attempt to reboot Twitter. The aim is to build a realtime social
feed free from the shackles of advertising, and instead a focus on creating an
experience tailored to its users and developers. Also, there seems to be a $50
cover.</p>

<p>Frankly, this undertaking seems ill advised, as does asking a bunch of people
for $50 for a username. App.net is taking on the giants of the Internet who
have worked for years to build product, developer community, etc. Having
worked with Twitter's APIs, I can say that Twitter has done a fantastic job of
advocating for developers and providing them the tools and data to innovate. I
can also say that I actually haven't noticed much impact from advertising, and
I consider myself a pretty heavy Twitter user. I also tend to have a hard time
differentiating between Rob Delaney's
<a href="https://twitter.com/Charmin/status/231413266251907073">digital</a>
<a href="https://twitter.com/HomeDepot/status/235083704358301697">harassment</a> and
properly promoted tweets.</p>

<p>Looking back, this project doesn't seem all that different from
<a href="https://joindiaspora.com/">Diaspora</a>. A small team aggravated with certain
aspects of larger services that they love puts out an app that is viable, but
is really a carbon copy of the original, with their own special twist.
Diaspora and App.net both want their users to have control over privacy, data,
and how much advertising is shoved in their face. Currently, Diaspora seems to
be completely off the radar, having made practically no dent in addressing its
original goals.</p>

<p>Building a product to address a flaw in someone else's product seems to be a
fools errand, particularly when the giants of real time social feeds are well
ensconced. Building a competitor product also doesn't seem like a great way to
convince the Internet that advertising is bad. Also, the Internet doesn't
really need convincing that ads are bad. I'm relatively sure that based on
diving click throughs, nonexistent conversion, and the mere existence of
banner blindness that Internet advertising industry also knows that its days
are numbered. Interestingly enough, the most fertile area of brand awareness
actually seems to be around using real time social media to engage in simple,
human ways. So I'm not sure how cutting brands out of the business model will
help here.</p>

<p>What surprises me most about the existence of app.net is how blatantly it
reinvents the wheel. The alpha was put out to show backers there was a real
app behind the video. However, aside from proving they can convince folks that
advertising control is bad, the actual app doesn't really do anything
innovative or different, at least that I can see. OK, you got me, there's
[data export|http://daltoncaldwell.com/we-did-it]. Realistically, this is an
alpha, there's virtually no data to export, so I would hardly consider this a
marvel of engineering. When Diaspora came onto the scene, they had actually
built something different, and innovative. Even Identi.ca attempted to
<a href="http://identi.ca/doc/faq">differentiate themselves</a> in functionality.</p>

<p>This entire project reeks of misdirected energy, and a "<a href="http://www.richard-banks.org/2007/07/built-here-syndrome.html">not built
here</a>"
mentality. Granted, I'm a huge fan of building things that make you happy,
it's part of what keeps me going as a developer. Truthfully, the thing I love
most about being a developer is that I can build whatever the fuck I want,
whether it helps, hurts, solves a problem, or complicates stuff. However, I
just can't help but feel this entire project is a form of lashing out. It
feels destructive to me to rally a group of smart people off of a platform
that's working well because of some flaws. Flaws which are really inherent
challenges building business on the Internet. I feel like a more effective
method of changing the environment would've been creating better ways to
monetize without having to resort to advertising.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death of the CTR]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2010/05/31/death-of-the-ctr/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2010/05/31/death-of-the-ctr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the dawn of online advertising, the gold standard of effectiveness has
been the CTR. This has made a lot of sense, since for the first time ever,
adertisers could leverage technology to figure out <em>exactly</em> how well they
were communicating. A user would click, and that click would be recorded. The
total number of clicks is compared against the total number of ads that are
put on the screen, and bingo, you know exactly how effective the campaign was.
Combine that number with more advanced analytics, such as tracking the user
past the initial click, onto the advertiser's site, and onto really
interesting places, like the confirmation page of an ecommerce site. This gave
advertisers really effective ways to quantify the effectiveness of a campaign.</p>

<p>What has been more difficult to quantify is the value of advertising in
creating engagement and awareness. Simply seeing a brand association between
host site and banner advertisement creates awareness of a brand. Seeing a
banner ad doesn't necessarily trigger immediate reactions (clicks), but can
trigger actions of the user later. Users may be inclined to purchase products
later on because of the brand awareness created by seeing banner ads. This is
awesome for advertisers, who get a return, albeit indirect, from banner
advertising, but it's far less awesome for publishers. That publisher put a
great deal of work to create content that people want to see, and advertising
fees are very common way of monetizng that work. However, CPMs are commonly
determined by CTR. If that publisher has a lousy CTR, as a result of something
terrible, like having a savvy demographic that knows <em>not</em> to click on ads,
then that publisher suffers.</p>

<p>Microsoft has long been a proponent of <a href="http://advertising.microsoft.com/research/engagement-mapping">measuring
engagement</a>, and
Google has recently mentioned rolling out tools that will track a user across
sessions on multiple sites. It's clear that the industry needs to move in this
direction, although hopefully it will move slowly and find ways to avoid
becoming a ubiquitous, Minority Report-style system where Skynet knows who you
are, and will show you ads for Banana Republic after you've purchased khakis
from the Gap. However, the rewards for publishers could be great if the larger
players in the industry were able to track users across websites, and even
devices.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
