<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: culture | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/culture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-19T20:02:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[never blame the button pusher]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/05/31/never-blame-the-button-pusher/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-31T00:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/05/31/never-blame-the-button-pusher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While having drinks with a colleague, the topic of improving execution within an
organization came up. There had been some problems in the past few years, but
this was an organization trying to operate in an unfamiliar way, and it was
suggested that problems could've been avoided by having a conscientious
operator. At one point in the conversation, the following was said;</p>

<blockquote><p>The people who push the buttons that cause problems should be fired. Heads
should roll.</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>I was a bit taken aback. In my short career, I've pushed a lot of buttons
that have caused <strong>a lot</strong> of problems. What was said was certainly not a
personal condemnation, but a statement made in frustration. Frustration born out
of seeing <code>human error</code> turn up as the root cause of most incidents, and not
enough improvement.</p>

<h2>Two problems</h2>

<p>The first is that the person pushing the button is probably just following a run
book. They might be brand new. The run book may have been given to them and
they were told not to deviate. That's the point of run books, after all, is to
allow ops teams to operate safely with proven procedures.</p>

<p>The second is that mistakes and accidents happen, no matter how much
preparation, automation and resiliency engineering goes into a service. <a href="https://twitter.com/beerops/status/571096463398187008">It is
inevitable that services will fail, and getting frustrated or angry about it is
irrational.</a></p>

<p>For both of these problems, it's extremely damaging to allow individuals to be
blamed for an incident. It destroys morale to see a team member singled out. A
rough lesson learned by one team member doesn't always translate to
institutional knowledge that helps prevent the next issues.</p>

<h2>The solution</h2>

<p>What we need to look for are things that can written down, codified and repeated
to ensure the same problem is prevented. If a run book procedure turns out to be
incorrect in a given set of circumstances, then it needs to be reexamined, by
the entire team. If an automation does the wrong thing, it needs to be fixed. If
a system allows actions to be taken that damage the effectiveness of the
service, you need to ask why those actions are allowed.</p>

<p>The point is, there is almost always an aspect of the system that can be changed
to ensure problems are avoided. Focusing on that will be way more productive
than focusing on individual actions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rigoletto]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/01/29/rigoletto/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/01/29/rigoletto</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From the <a href="http://www.wqxr.org/#!/blogs/operavore/2013/jan/29%0A/review-metropolitan-operas-rat-pack-rigoletto-hits-jackpot/">WQXR review</a> of Rigoletto at
the Met</p>

<blockquote><p>As much as Verdi has resisted updating, his tale of a nasty hunchback court
jester whose daughter is killed by his own need for revenge arrived here in
the early-'80s as a gangster movie courtesy of Jonathan Miller and the
visiting English National Opera. More recently in Wales, the Duke of Mantua's
decadent court became the Oval Office. Mayer's production did everything that
a Las Vegas setting threatens to do — colors never seen in nature, pole
dancing, glitzy satellite chandeliers (not unlike the Met's) and even Met
titles with modern English colloquialism. Some wondered aloud why the
translation even bothered to keep names like "Duke." Why not Frank and Sammy?</p></blockquote>

<p>Having never experienced an Opera before, and not knowing anything about the
plot of Rigoletto other than what I read in Playbill, the modern setting and
translation went a long way in helping me understand Verdi. In general, the
few productions I've seen in the past few years have had odd elements
alongside original text that seemed to have been put there to soften the
harshness of unfamiliar colloquialisms. Superhero costumes in Shakespeare, and
even the staging of Rigoletto help to make this otherwise stuffy content
accessible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
