<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: team | The Technician]]></title>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/blog/categories/team/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-18T14:43:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Henry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chat and Dense Communication]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/08/30/slack/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-30T10:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2015/08/30/slack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven't noticed, communication among teams (distributed or local) is a
thing that people care a lot about. For my team, we specifically care about
density of quality communication across mediums. We're an ops team, and
being able to broadcast status and information is critically important. As we
work, we don't want to have to re-communicate across mediums, but we still want
to make sure the right people hear us and provide feedback.</p>

<p>As our team was searching for ways to accomplish this, we started using the
ubiquitous and humble webhook to push information between systems. At first,
we simply started pushing Pull Request comments into our Slack channel. This
immediately increased our velocity, as we found ourselves seamlessly moving
discussions from traditionally asynchronous mediums (Github Pull Requests) to
more real time mediums (Slack, In Person).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Eventually, we started adding more sources to chat via Slack integrations. Our
project tracking tool was a clear next step, as most of the information we
were pouring into it was helpful to others. Team members reacting to status
updates with pointers and questions was yet another boost to velocity of
information. Including brief comments of intent and even full blown
plans gave us a hook for correcting mistakes before they even happened.</p>

<p><blockquote><p><b>Dense Communication</b> - Extremely high signal to noise ratio textual<br/>information that's automatically compiled from different sources and intended to<br/>cross mediums.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The flip side of this was that looking through our chat was like drinking from a
firehose. There was an immense amount of fragmented, context-less information
flowing at any given time, so much so that it was easy to drown. The uninitiated
considered our channel noisy, which is a fair assessment. Those who didn't have
access to the cornucopia of links ubiquitous to our channel had an even harder
time trying to make sense of things. Some even believed the noise was
distracting.</p>

<p>However, for those of us deep in the shit, we found that we were on the same
page more frequently. In person communication became high trust, where one
speaker could say the wrong thing and the listener could hear the right thing,
thanks largely to shared context. We found ourselves responding to status
updates made via integrations with helpful suggestions, requests to clarify,
corrections, etc. Proposed plans were reviewed earlier, and noted blocks
were busted more quickly. In general, we reacted more, contributed more, and as
a result, had better outcomes.</p>

<p>To critics of these practices, we say that <a href="https://twitter.com/postwait/status/637935373327446016">team productivity is more important
than individual productivity</a>.
As humans walk down the streets of New York, there are a million stimuli, some
gross, and some deadly. To say that people can't read and filter a few lines of
text is a cop out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy Fallacy]]></title>
    <link href="http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/04/14/policy-fallacy/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-14T19:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chr.ishenry.com/2013/04/14/policy-fallacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"The Navy is a master plan designed by geniuses for execution by idiots. If you're not an idiot, but find yourself in the Navy, you can only operate well by pretending to be one."
-Herman Wouk, The Caine Mutiny</p></blockquote>

<p>The worst arguments I've ever had were with people who weren't willing to bend
on policy in situations where the policy made no sense. Context is everything,
and most policy is made for a situation that has likely come and gone.</p>

<p>People with judgment will recognize this, especially in the context of running
startups. Hopefully, they were the same person that made the original policy,
and can see that things have changed. Smart companies have fewer policies,
implicitly trusting their teams to make the right decision.</p>

<p><a href="/images/user/use_good_judgement.png"><img src="/images/user/use_good_judgement.png" alt="Use Good Judgement" /></a></p>

<p>From <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/HubSpot/the-hubspot-culture-code-creating-a-company-we-love/56">Hubspot's Presentation Culture Code: Creating A Lovable Company</a></p>

<p>The takeaway here is that you can judge organizations and people based on how beholden they are to policy. Smart ones let you make smart decisions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
